Presenting Studio Khara's 1st Production
Rebuild of Evangelion: Prelude
It shows up now , of all times!?
Geez...
Due to the present state of emergency,
all phone lines have been disabled.
No good, huh?
My cell phone has no signal,
and the buses and trains are shut down too.
Shinji
Wait for me
until I get there
'kay?
Feast your eyes
on this!
I guess it'll be impossible to meet her now.
I've got no choice. I should head to a shelter.
All missiles have hit the target!
Sorry I made you wait!
The target is still unharmed. It's continuing to advance towards Tokyo-3.
The Air Force is unable to stop it!
Throw everything at it! Have even the 4th Division open fire!
Spare no expense! Destroy the target at all costs!
How the hell?! We made direct hits!!
The tank battalion was completely destroyed.
Missiles and artillery are useless...
It's pointless! This type of firepower's not going to get us anywhere!
So, it has an AT Field after all?
Yes...
Conventional weapons are useless against an Angel.
Understood. We'll deploy it according to plan.
No way... it can't be...!
They're going to use an N2 Mine?!
Get down!
We did it!
It seems you won't be needed this time.
Shockwave incoming!
Are you okay?
Yeah... but I think I got some sand in my mouth.
Great! Here, help me out...
Get ready...
And PUSH!
Thanks! Couldn't have done it myself.
No, I should be thanking you, Katsuragi-san.
Call me Misato, alright?
It's nice to meet you, Ikari Shinji-kun.
Yeah.
What is the target's status?
Due to radio interference, the target cannot be confirmed.
With that explosion, it must be obliterated.
Restoring visual.
And that was our trump card...
How is this possible...
Goddamn monster!
Thank God my Renault still works!
It'd be no joke for this car to die on me, since I've still got 12 payments left on the lease...
Anyway, I called ahead to reserve an express train for us,
so we might still make it in time!
Say, don't you have any questions for me, Shinji-kun?
N-no.
I've been the only one talking here, you know!
Sorry...
Oh, it's nothing to apologize over,
but I was sure you were going to ask "What was that giant thing?,"
or maybe, "What's going on here?"
you know, those sorts of things?
Um, well...
I don't see the point, since I didn't think you'd give me an answer anyway.
Wow, you sure jump to wrong conclusions, don't you?
That's something adults do, not teenagers!
It's okay.
I'm just following my directions.
Oh?... never mind then.
Just for your information, that thing was a mysterious life form we call an "Angel."
The 4th Angel...
It possesses an astounding regenerative capacity.
Complete by itself, it is a nearly-perfect living creature.
Of course it can regenerate.
Because Angels partook of the Fruit of Life, you mean?
Yes. They exist to exterminate us... we, who partook of the Fruit of Wisdom.
The gate is closing. Please be careful.
"Secret Military Agency NERV"...?
Yes, it's a private organization under the direct control of the U.N..
That's where my father is?
Well, yeah...
Do you know what your dad's job is?
"Work of utmost importance in the protection of humanity."
That's what my teacher said.
From here on, you will be in command of this operation.
Show us what you can do.
Understood.
Ikari-kun, I have to admit that nothing in our arsenal is effective against the target.
So you claim you can defeat this thing?
NERV exists for that very purpose.
Are we going to where my father is?
Yeah, I imagine he'll be there.
Father...
By the way, did your father send you an ID card?
Ah, yeah.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Come!
Ikari Gendo.
Here, read this please.
NERV.
My father's work.
Is there something I'm needed for?
Of course. He wouldn't send me a letter if he didn't need me for something.
I see, you don't get along with your father.
---me neither.
Amazing!
A real GeoFront!
That's right.
And that is our secret base; NERV Headquarters.
It's humanity's fortress, the cornerstone to rebuilding our world.
Let's see... from the terminal's Western exit,
Go north to the 3rd gate and take a right.
Then, we need to take Route 8...
Could they have made this facility any more complicated?
Hmm... this looks like the correct route...
Um, are we lost?
I'm just not used to this place yet.
Either way, if we keep heading forward we'll eventually get there!
Secondary cooling cycle complete.
All personnel, evacuate the tank immediately.
I want the left arm's conductive plating defrosted and ready to go
within the next three minutes!
And don't forget that apoptosis data!
Roger!
Attention Professor Akagi: Chief Operations Officer Lt. Colonel Katsuragi, together with one young boy, have arrived at Shaft S36.
What a surprise.
She's late yet again.
Ah... Ritsuko!
You're 12 minutes past schedule. You were taking so long, I came to greet you personally, Lt. Colonel Katsuragi.
We're short on staff and out of time.
Eh... Sorry!
Is this the boy?
Yup.
I'm the Chief Engineer and Administrator of NERV's Project E, Akagi Ritsuko.
It's nice to meet you.
M-me too.
Well then, I'll leave things here to you.
It'll be their first meeting in 3 years...
Deputy Commander! The target has begun to move!
Understood.
All units, Level One battle stations!
I repeat, all units, Level One battle stations!
Ground forces, prepare for combat!
Ikari Shinij-kun, there's something I want to show you.
The ultimate man-made multipurpose fighting machine. The artificial human, Evangelion.
That is Unit 01.
Mankind's very last trump card.
This is my father's work?
Correct.
It's been a while.
Father...
Prepare to sortie.
Sortie?!
But Unit 00 is still frozen, isn't it?
Unless... You intend to use Unit 01?
There is no other choice.
Ikari Shinji-kun...?
Y-Yes?
You will pilot it.
Why did you call me here, Father?
For the same reason you're thinking.
I'm supposed to pilot this and fight that thing I just saw outside?
Correct.
I don't want to! What are you saying all of a sudden?!
I thought you didn't need me! That's why you left!
I need you now, so I called for you.
Why... me?
Because no one else can.
I can't do it...
I've never seen or heard of this thing.
I just can't!
We'll explain it to you.
No...
I can't do it!
There's no way I can do this!
If you're going to pilot it, do it now. If not...
Leave!
So, we've been found...
Armored hulls 1 through 8 have been breeched!
Shinji-kun, there isn't much time.
Widespread fire alarms in Block D. Closing all fire doors in the area.
Pilot it!
No!
...sure, I came all this way... but this is impossible!
Shinji-kun, why did you come here?
Don't run away. You have to face your father... and more importantly, yourself.
I know that! But I just can't  do this!
Fuyutsuki.
Wake up Rei.
Can we use her?
She's not dead.
Understood.
Rei.
Yes.
The backup is useless. We need you once more.
Switch Unit 01's core unit to the L-00 type and reactivate it!
Roger. Suspending current tasks. Reactivating.
Entering reactivation command.
I knew it. I was never needed...
The Target has broken through the final defense line,
and is proceeding to head right above us.
Are you alright?
I mustn't run away, I mustn't run away, I mustn't run away, I mustn't run away...
I mustn't run away!
I'll do it.
I'll pilot it.
Third cooling cycle, complete.
Flywheel rotation shutdown.
Unlocking the connectors.
No problems with the auxiliary power.
Shutdown signal plug extraction complete.
Roger, inserting entry plug.
Unlocking spinal conductive network. Prepare for connection.
Probe needle insertion complete.
Prime sync established. Psychological corruption values within acceptable range.
Maintaining range between plus-02 and minus-05.
Locking down interior array.
Roger, starting first contact.
Flooding Entry Plug.
W-What is this?
It's alright.
Once the LCL fills your lungs, it will provide oxygen directly to your blood.
You'll get used to it.
Main power source connection complete.
Roger.
Starting second contact.
Initializing interface.
A-10 nerve connection is normal.
LCL ionization levels normal.
Set Japanese as the linguistic norm for cognitive interface.
No problems detected with initial contacts.
Communication lines open.
Points on the list up to 1405, all clear.
Measuring synapse levels. Synchronization rate, 41.3%.
And he's not even wearing a plug suit! Amazing!
Harmonics are in normal levels. Everything's under control.
We are ready!
Prepare to launch!
Release primary lock bolts!
Release confirmed.
Initiating retraction of umbilical bridge.
Release secondary lock bolts!
Removing primary restraints.
Proceeding to remove secondary restraints.
Disengaging safety systems 01 through 15.
Disengagement confirmed.
Unit 01 is now free.
Internal power supply, fully charged.
No problems with the external power socket.
Understood. Move Unit 01 to the launch pad.
No problems with the positioning of any of the linear rail tracks.
Electromagnetic induction system, working normally.
Unit 01 is now moving to K-52.
Launch sequence is proceeding normally.
Eva has arrived at the launch terminal hub.
Launch tube clear. All green!
Launch preparations complete.
Understood.
I have your approval?
Absolutely.
Our future depends on defeating the Angels.
Ikari, you're absolutely sure about this?
LAUNCH!
Are you alright, Shinji-kun?
Y-Yes.
Release the final safety lock!
Evangelion Unit 01, lift off!
Shinji-kun...
for now, just concentrate on walking.
Walk...
It walked!
Shinji-kun, stay alert!
Hurry...
Hurry and get back up!
Shinji-kun, calm down!
It's not really your arm that's being hurt!
What happened to Eva's defensive systems?
Signal inactive!
The field isn't expending.
It's not working?
The left arm is damaged!
Circuits are going off-line!
Shinji-kun, dodge!!
Frontal cranium is fracturing!
Its armor can't withstand much more!
Cranial damage, severity unknown!
Operational integrity compromised!
What's the status?
Synchro graph inverting! Pulse entering reflux!
Cut off the circuits! Block the flow!
We can't!
The signal's being refused, we can't get through!
Shinji-kun's status?!
No response from the monitoring system. Condition unknown!
Unit 01 has gone silent.
Misato!
That's it!
Abort the operation! Pilot rescue has top priority!
Emergency plug ejection!
We can't! It's not responding!
What?!
The Eva has reactivated!
Impossible...
It should be knocked out!
Has it gone...
Berserk?!
We've won.
An AT-Field?
It's pointless. Unless the AT Field is breached...
...you can't do anything to an Angel.
Left arm restored!
Amazing!
Unit 01 has also raised an AT-Field!
Angel phase space is being neutralized.
No. It's corroding it.
It broke through that AT-Field like it was nothing...
What is Eva's status?
Is this Eva's...
True form?
Have you decided on a name?
If it's a boy, Shinji. If it's a girl, then Rei.
Shinji...
Rei...
Shinji... Ayanami.
Shinji...
Rei...
Rei... Ikari...?
No...
Ayanami... Rei!
An unfamiliar ceiling...
The attack of the fourth Angel, and its defeat...
Then the acquisition of the Third Child...
And the activation of Eva Unit 01...
Overall the plan is progressing well.
Well, except for the colossal expense necessary to repair Unit 01.
Compared to Unit 00 in cryo-suspension,
that is hardly a problem.
Eva Unit 01's recovery operation is complete.
Right now, it's being locked into Cage 6.
A full-systems check will commence at 10:00 hours.
And the recording from when it went berserk?
It was blank. Absolutely nothing was recorded.
And so, we have no idea what the cause was.
Our absolute confidence in its combat performance... may be a bit misplaced.
As long as it can fight the 5th Angel, minor bugs are tolerable.
No need for concern.
We'll continue deployment of Unit 01.
And Unit 02 and its pilot in Germany are under deployment qualification exams.
The construction of Unit 03 is also progressing as planned.
It's your responsibility to make proper use of NERV and the Evas.
We earnestly hope you will not disappoint us.
That's right. Defeating the Angels is but one step in fulfilling our contract with Lilith.
Human Instrumentality Project
Top Secret
27th Interim Report
The Human Instrumentality Project...
Its execution is our ultimate goal.
I understand. Everything will go according to SEELE's scenario.
An Angel leaves quite a mark when it's destroyed after it loses its AT Field.
The blood is like a lake from hell...
It's got the same nasty feeling as the Second Impact.
Our Eva can defeat an Angel...
That alone will give humanity a glimmer of hope.
Well, looks the pilot of hope just woke up.
Paging Chief Internist Dr. Ugai. Dr. Ugai.
Please contact Dr. Azuma in the Emergency Surgical Ward as soon as possible.
The B Incident Grand Rounds will momentarily begin, according to schedule.
Would the event directors please make their way to conference room 2? Thank you.
Tokyo-3 Geo-Front District F
Ikari, Shinji
Change of address
Male
Head of household
Resident Registration
Former location omitted
Alone?
Yes, he's been assigned quarters in Block 6. That all right?
Yes.
Is that really okay?
Shinji-kun?
It's fine. I'm always alone.
It's always the same wherever I go.
What?!
Like I was saying, I'm taking Shinji back to my place to live with me.
I have authorization from above.
Don't worry, I wouldn't lay a hand on a little boy like him.
Of course you won't! Honestly, what are you thinking?! Don't even say things like this!
She could never take a joke...
All right, we're gonna having a party tonight!
What for?
To welcome my new roommate, of course!
So you've decided to move?
Yes, I never thought this city would become a battlefield.
Indeed! My husband wants me and the children to leave here too!
I heard that just today, over 100 people left the city.
This may be a fortress city, but those people at NERV seem rather incompetent.
I get chills just thinking about what happened yesterday.
I know...
Sorry,
but we're going to take a slight detour.
Where to?
Someplace special.
This city...
...seems so lonely, doesn't it?
It's time.
Amazing...
Buildings are sprouting out of the ground!
This is the special fortress-city for intercepting Angels.
Tokyo-3.
This is our city...
And the city that you protected.
Looks like your things have already been delivered.
To tell the truth, I've only moved to this city recently.
All right, come on in.
Um...
Pardon the intrusion.
Shinji-kun, this is your home now.
I'm... I'm home.
Welcome home.
Ah yeah...
It's a little messy in here, but try to ignore it.
Is this...
...a little?
Oh sorry, could you put the food in the fridge please?
Ah, sure!
Ice...
Snacks...
And nothing but beer?
What kind of life does she lead?
Let's dig in!
Let's eat...
Ah, I love it! This is what makes life worth living!
Not hungry? For instant food, it's pretty good.
Well... I'm just not used to this sort of meal.
No! You just can't be so picky!
No, that's not it... Um...
Isn't this fun...?
Having a meal with another person?
Uh... yes.
All right!
Since this is your home now, feel free to just let loose!
Y-Yes...
Come on... This "Yes, yes, yes, yes." is getting on my nerves...
You're a boy aren't you?! Show some backbone, will you!
Yes.
Well, whatever.
Once you'll get in the bath, all those bad feelings will just wash away in an instant!
Bathing lets you wash your life anew.
M-M-Misato-san!
What?
Ah, him? He's my pet bird. They call them hot spring penguins.
Birds like that actually exist?!
They used to be a lot more common 15 years ago.
His name is Pen-pen.
He'll be your other roommate in this house.
Anyway... shouldn't you be covering that?
Maybe I'm being overly flamboyant... he might be able to see right through me.
Katsuragi Misato-san...
She's not a bad person.
Bathing lets you wash your life anew!
I tend to remember bad things when I'm in a bath...
How was Rei doing?
You went to her hospital this afternoon, no?
There are no problems. Preparing to restart the frozen Unit 00 is more important.
Are you sure about using your son? His mental state seems to be very unstable.
Don't worry about him. His condition will give us the perfect pretext to reinstate Unit 00.
We'll proceed according to Lt. Colonel Katsuragi's suggestion, then.
Shinji's
Room
Change of Address
Ikari,  Shinji
Even without a preliminary report, they suddenly selected him as the Third Child.
And as if in response, the Fourth Angel attacks.
In addition, Commander Ikari forces his son to pilot.
I certainly feel very uneasy about that fact...
But still, even after successfully defeating that Angel, I feel surprisingly...
unhappy.
Another unfamiliar ceiling...
No surprise...
Nothing about this city is familiar.
This is your home now.
Why am I even here?
Shinji-kun? I'm coming in.
I forgot to tell you something.
You've done a wonderful thing worth praising today.
You should be proud.
Goodnight, Shinji-kun.
Hang in there.
Sorry, transfer kid. I had to hit ya.
To settle the score with you.
Real sorry. That guy's little sister was injured in that big incident the other day.
That's just how it is with him.
It's not like I piloted it because I wanted to.
How is this something people would praise me for?
Why do I have to get hit just because I piloted the Eva?
Is everything alright, Shinji-kun?
Yes.
Within each Angel there is a central core.
The only way to defeat an Angel directly is to destroy that core.
Therefore, center on target, then pull the trigger.
This way, you can dispose of them accurately if you master the process.
Okay.
Good. Continue practicing like this in induction mode.
Still, I'm quite surprised Shinji-kun suddenly changed his mind about piloting...
That boy only gets through life by silently obeying whatever people tell him, doesn't he?
Center on target, then pull the trigger.
Which reminds me...
Wasn't Shinji-kun hit by one of his classmates at his new school?
Is our pilot security sufficient?
There's no problem with our intelligence department's surveillance.
Besides, it wasn't very bad.
It would better if we stayed out of his private life.
Doesn't he live with you?
His maintenance is your responsibility too, you know.
That's just it.
It's difficult... He's far more naïve than I expected.
Hah, complaining already?
You were the one who was so adamant about taking him in.
Quiet, you.
You're right, he doesn't have much of a personality for making friends.
Have you heard of the "Hedgehog's dilemma"?
Hedgehog? The little spiky things?
Hedgehogs have a hard time sharing warmth with other hedgehogs.
The closer they become, the more they hurt each other.
People are like that as well.
Like with Shinji-kun right now.
The more pain his heart endures, the more afraid he becomes.
Well, eventually he'll realize.
Becoming an adult means drawing close and growing apart over and over...
...and discovering the way to avoid wounding one another.
I certainly hope so.
Anyway, when are we gonna get budget approval to upgrade Block B here?
Eva's maintenance and armaments are the top priority.
Maybe there's no money left?
My ass is freezing!
An emergency call...
I'll go on ahead.
We have direct visual of inbound object.
E747 has also confirmed the object.
Analysis indicates Pattern Blue. There's no doubt. It's the fifth Angel.
All hands, level one battle stations!
Roger, ground-to-air missiles ready!.
Tokyo-3 entering combat configuration.
Retracting central block.
Center block and Districts One through Seven's retraction is complete.
All governmental departments have been notified.
Target continuing inbound movement.
The anti-air interception system is 48% activated.
Status of noncombatants and civilians?
We've already received a complete evacuation report.
All Elementary and Middle School student classes, please gather in your designated blocks.
There is a lost child at shelter number 323 in Sector Seven.
It's happening again.
Just text again?
They're controlling the broadcast.
They won't show us regular citizens anything.
Not even a big event like this!
This is a waste of tax money.
Some people just aren't happy unless they burn through some ammo.
The Japanese government is demanding we send out the Evangelion.
How annoying. It's not like we weren't going to do that without their orders.
We've started the entry. Ionizing LCL.
Father's not even watching me... Why am I piloting this again?
People hate me for this...
Hey, I wanna talk to you about something, alone.
What about?
Just for a minute, okay?
Alright, alright...
Right, right, and then-
Class Rep!
What?
We, uh, both need to take a leak!
Geez, make it quick!!
So, what's this about?
I want to see it at least once before I die!
That battle up there?
This is the real deal! If I don't go now, who knows when I'll get another chance...
Jeez, Kensuke, what is it with you?
"If you waste this moment, you may waste everything."
Come on... Just help me get past the gate.
Guess I've got no choice. You're a real slave to your passions, aren't you?
Shinji-kun, are you ready for launch?
Yes.
Remember. Continuous Gatling gun fire as you neutralize its AT Field.
Just like in practice. You'll be fine.
Yes...
Launch!
Incredible! This was worth the trouble!
Yes! This is what I've been waiting for!
It's here.
Center on target, then pull the trigger.
Expanding A.T. Field.
Proceed according to the plans, okay, Shinji-kun?
Yes.
Idiot! All that smoke is obscuring the target!
The heck? He's gettin' his ass kicked!
He's fine!
We're sending up a spare rifle!
Grab it!
Shinji-kun...? Shinji-kun?!
Oh man... Your beating must have shaken him up.
Sh-Shut up!
Umbillical Cable has been severed!
Eva switching to internal power supply!
Operational time remaining is 4 minutes 53 seconds!
It's coming this way!
Shinji-kun, are you all right?! Shinji-kun!
Damage report?
No problems. He's good to go.
Shinji-kun's classmates?!
What are they doing there?!
Why isn't he fighting back?!
Maybe he can't move freely... because we're here!?
Unit 01 will reach operational time limit in 3 minutes 28 seconds!
Palm armor overheating. Damage, 58%.
Shinji-kun, let those two into the cockpit!
Once they're in, get out of there! We'll start over afterwards.
You two, get in, quickly!
What the-- Is this water?!
My camera! My camera!
System restarting.
Palm surface meltdown has reached the 3rd protective layer!
Now's your chance! Retreat!
Use escape route 34. Retreat on the eastern side of the mountain.
Hey, transfer kid, she said "retreat!"
I mustn't run away... I mustn't run away... I mustn't run away...
Transfer kid!
Progressive Knife equipped!
Shinji-kun, listen to my order! Fall back now!
Shinji-kun!
That idiot!
Unit 01 will reach operational time limit in 30 seconds.
28, 27, 26...
25, 24, 23, 22...
13, 12, 11, 10...
9, 8, 7, 6, 5...
4, 3, 2, 1...
Eva Unit 01 has ceased operation.
Target has completely disintegrated.
Why did you ignore my orders?
I'm sorry.
I am your operational supervisor, am I not?
Yes.
It's your duty to follow the orders I give you.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Make sure this doesn't happen again.
Do you really understand what I'm telling you?
Yes, I understand, Misato-san.
It's fine, we won, didn't we?
I'll pilot it if you tell me to. Isn't that what you want?
That's enough. Go back and get some rest.
Next stop is Nagao Pass. Nagao Pass.
Please exit to the right.
He doesn't plan on coming home...
That idiot.
Ikari, Ikari Shinji.
What's this? He just got here, and he's already absent?
Oh well. Now then, I'll hand back the tests from the other day.
I've had enough of this!
Please take me back to Misato-san!
Did your little stroll clear things up for you, Ikari Shinji-kun?
Not really. It didn't really matter. Nothing does.
I don't have any freedom anyway.
I have no choice but to pilot Eva, do I?
That's the only reason my father called for me, after all.
Fine. I'll pilot it.
If that's what everyone wants, that's what I'll do.
You talk about everyone else, but what about yourself?
I know I can't do this. I bet everybody else does, too.
But Ayanami is hurt, and you and father want...
Cut it out!
This has nothing to do with anyone else!
You need to decide if you want to be the pilot for the Eva.
You're free to go if you want to.
You have all the freedom you want. Do as you please!
In the end, your son's actions followed the plan to the letter.
Yes. Next we must make him and Rei get closer.
All is according to plan.
A scenario written out 14 years ago.
These poor children's fates have already been determined.
Don't you find that a bit harsh?
C'mon, hurry it up! And don't hold back!
If you don't do this, I won't feel like it's settled!
Well, that's just the kind of straightforward guy he is. I'm counting on you.
Now we're even. I'm sorry for hitting you, Ikari.
Go, go, Kayoko!
If you lose, you're buying us a pizza!
That's it! Go, go, go!
In your dreams!!
Please! Give me one more chance!!
Ew, the boys are peeping!
Pervs!
That's naughty!
Suzuhara's gaze is so lewd!
Ikari-kun~!
Ayanami Rei, age 14.
She was the first candidate chosen by the Marduk Institute.
The First Child.
Specifically, she is the exclusive operator of the prototype Evangelion, Unit 00.
Her personal history is blank. Completely erased.
So, to save her, my father...
Critical error in startup system!
Failures in Stage 3 routines!
Nervous system elements rejected.
The main transmission system is scrambled! It's overflowing!
Neural pulse flow reversing! I'm unable to stop it!
Direct camera feed, down!
Entry plug unstable. Eva is refusing to release it!
Abort contacts. Close off all circuits up to number six.
I can't! The signal won't go through!
Unit 00 is out of control!
Abort the test. Cut all power.
Yes, sir!
Unit 00 has switched to auxiliary power.
35 seconds to total system shutdown.
Failsafe system has yet to activate.
It's dangerous! Please step back!
The auto-eject has activated!
Oh no!
We still cannot control Unit 00!
Quickly, release specialized Bakelite!
Rei!
Ten seconds to complete shutdown!
8, 7, 6, 5...
4, 3, 2, 1.
Unit 00 has ceased all activity.
Rei, are you alright?
Rei!
That's good.
It was so sudden. I couldn't believe it.
It was deleted from the official report, but it's an undisputed fact.
Unit 00 just went berserk, and is still being unfrozen.
Isn't that a bit hasty?
The Angels have reappeared. It's our top priority to reinforce our military strength.
That's true, but...
We've already run reactivation tests with Rei.
Unit 00 itself is ready.
Once the adjustments to the nerve connections are complete.
It's so we can re-deploy it soon, isn't it?
Ayanami...
Why is she always alone?
Eva Unit 01 is beginning third coolant phase.
Please set all systems in Cage 6 to phase three.
Copying the all-range data of the entry plug to Melchior. Data sent.
Begin third cooling phase.
Copying situation data from Casper to Melchior.
Currently, Unit 01's plug depth is at 0,8. It's within acceptable measurement range.
T-minus 150 minutes to Unit 00's conductive systems restart and testing.
Roger. Routine synchronization test, Program 508 is now complete.
Good work, Shinji-kun.
So, what's it like living with him?
It's alright. I'm getting used to it.
Still a little nervous?
It's not your first time living with a man, is it?
This isn't like 8 years ago.
This time, it's not an intimate relationship.
I don't know about that...
Shinji-kun is still here because of you, isn't he?
You're wrong there.
It's probably because his father's here.
He wants his father to acknowledge him.
To pat him on the shoulder.
To praise him, even if it's just one word.
I think he wants a love that will wipe away his loneliness.
He's conflicted over his father, just like you are, Misato.
I wonder why Commander Ikari acts so distant with his own son.
And it looks like he talks to Rei a lot.
It's a terrible balance.
Lately, it seems like men have no interest in anything other than themselves.
It's a tough time to be a woman, isn't it?
Well, then...
It's about time. I have to head back.
You're a worker bee, as always.
Take these if you're going home, Misato. It's Shinji-kun's official security card,
...and Ayanami Rei's renewed card.
I forgot about these.
Could you ask Shinji to give this to her?
Alright.
Ayanami Rei...
Why was father smiling with her...?
Why won't he smile for me?
Excuse me...
Excuse me, it's Ikari!
Ayanami, I'm coming in.
Could these be Ayanami's?
Oh, no... Um... I...!
I didn't mean to...
Could you move?
U-um...!
What is it?
Um... I was... Um...
That is...
I... I was asked to... I mean...
The uhhh...
The card! The c-card was renewed and... and I c-came to deliver it...
So... So... It's not like I was trying to...
Ritsuko-san said she forgot to give it to you. Honestly.
I rang the doorbell, but no one answered... and the door was unlocked, so...
Offices in the Central Dogma are currently accessible.
Group 3 visitors are requested to please use Direct Gate 4.
Here's your new card, Ayanami. Ritsuko-san left it with me.
Sorry about before.
What for?
Say, Ayanami... Aren't you afraid?
About piloting that Evangelion again.
Why should I be?
I heard you got hurt in that test...
So... Are you really okay?
Yes. I'm okay.
But... aren't you afraid it will go berserk again?
Or we could lose to an Angel and die!
You're Commander Ikari's son, aren't you?
You don't have faith in your father's work?
Of course not! Not from a father like him.
Um...
Monitored object is proceeding past the Odawara defense Line.
Object analysis complete.
Pattern blue. Angel confirmed.
As we thought. The 6th Angel.
Yes.
Prepare Unit 01 for sortie.
Prepare to launch Unit 01!
Anti-air interception weapons armed.
The target is passing above Lake Ashinoko.
Evangelion Unit 01 is ready to launch!
Launch!
High energy reaction detected inside the target!
What?!
Don't tell me...!
Get out of there!
Lower synchronization rate to minimum!
Deploy blast shield!
Abort intercept! Begin emergency recovery of Unit 01!
We can't! The catapult has melted. It's unusable!
What about the AT-Field?
Fully raised. Structural integrity is holding, but barely!
No! No more of this!
Let me out! Get me out of here, father!!
Abort the operation!
Place top priority on the pilot's safety! Force eject the plug!
That won't do.
If the pilot is taken out, Eva's AT-Field will completely disappear!
Things will go from bad to worse.
But...
There's no other choice...
Emergency recovery! Blow the explosive bolts!
The target has ceased fire.
Unit 01 retrieved. Sending to Cage 99!
Rescue team, stand by!
First priority is cooling the LCL in the plug!
Pilot confirmed! His heart rate is weak.
Boost plug suit life support to max! Begin cardiac massage!
Understood!
Pulse confirmed!
Forcefully eject the plug!
Stabilizing possible rupture point in the interior.
Begin emergency LCL draining!
At once!
Draining LCL.
Hurry emergency treatment!
The target is currently invading from above.
It's in the midst of drilling through to the Geo-Front.
Its objective is a direct attack on our NERV HQ, is it?
Well then, let's hear the results of each department's analysis.
Judging from the previous battle...
...the target automatically engages any enemy within a certain range.
Meaning it's impossible for Eva to engage it in close combat, right?
How's its AT Field?
Still operational. And to make matters worse...
with its phase pattern constantly shifting, the field's surface is unstable.
Neutralizing it will be very difficult.
According to Magi's calculations...
...to pierce the enemy's AT Field, we'd need to drop so many aerial N2 Mines that it would destroy NERV HQ as well.
The Magi 2 at Matsushiro reached the same conclusion.
Right now, the Japanese government and U.N. Forces are petitioning NERV HQ to do just that.
An easy suggestion to make when they're not the ones in danger.
If this place falls, then all is lost.
However, the drill has already breached the second layer of armor plating.
It's already begun penetrating the third.
The estimated time from today until it has passed through all 22 layers,
reaching the area above HQ, is 12:06:54 AM tomorrow morning.
We have ten hours and fourteen minutes.
To make matters worse, Unit 00 needs to be calibrated before it's operational.
Unit 01 is also currently unmovable due to its previous injury.
The situation sure isn't favorable.
We're certainly backed into a corner.
Should we wave the white flag?
Maybe... but before we do, I have a little something I'd like to try.
The intelligence division should be aware of the JSSDF's secret weapon, right?
Still, though, it's reckless to use this in an operation, Operations Chief Katsuragi.
"Reckless" is a bit rude.
In can be done within the remaining nine hours, and it's the best shot we've got.
Operation Yashima...
As the name suggests, we'll be taking electrical power from all over Japan.
And then direct it toward JSSDF's secret prototype weapon, a high power positron cannon.
Since it's unfinished, and can't be used on its own, it's been modified for Eva to control it.
Convincing the U.N. Forces is one thing, but the Ministry of Home Affairs and JSSDF, too?
Let's just say they owe me a few favors.
You sure are good at what you do.
From midnight tonight to before dawn tomorrow, the entire country will experience a large-scale blackout.
We ask for everyone's cooperation. I repeat...
We ask for everyone's cooperation.
Alright. Let's go.
Yeah.
From midnight tonight to before dawn tomorrow, the entire country will experience a large-scale blackout.
We ask for everyone's cooperation.
The Angel has penetrated through the 7th armored plate!
What's the status of our energy system?
Power will be fed directly from the Shingotenba substation and two backup generators!
Superconductor power lines now being laid towards lower Futagoyama.
The transformer relay system is scheduled to be up and running at 10:50 PM Japan time.
How's progress on the sniping system?
No problems in assembly. We'll have no trouble making it by the operation start time.
What is Unit 01's status?
It's currently being outfitted with G-type sniping equipment.
It will be ready to deploy in two hours.
Roger that! All that's left now is the pilot.
But I wonder... Will he be willing to pilot it again?
What do you plan to do about Unit 01's pilot?
It's too soon to test the dummy plug system.
We have no other practical means other than letting the current pilot handle it.
In the worst case, do we brainwash him?
If things don't work out, there's always Rei.
Rei in Unit 01? Isn't that a bit too risky?
We must use whatever means are available to us.
We still have eight Angels we must defeat.
And then, we realize our goal...
I hate it... piloting the Eva.
If I do it well, no one praises me for doing it.
If I fail, everyone will hate me. Or, even worse, I could just die.
Why am I even here?
I thought things would change here.
That maybe good things would happen.
I didn't come here to be put through hell.
So you plan to spend the rest of your life running away from everything unpleasant?
Live?
Why am I alive, anyway?
I used to think I didn't have a choice in the matter.
Whether it's my father or Misato-san, no one really needs me.
If I couldn't pilot Eva, there would be no need for me.
That's why I have no choice but to pilot Eva.
That's why I'm able to stay here.
But when I pilot my Eva, I...
This ceiling again...
Is this all I get for piloting that thing?
Ayanami...?
You were here the whole time?
I'm here to tell you about the schedule for Operation Yashima, which will commence at midnight tomorrow.
Pilots Ikari and Ayanami are to report at Terminal 2 at 19:30.
At 20:00, Unit 01, accompanied by Unit 00, will be transferred.
Launch is scheduled at 20:05.
By 20:30, they will arrive at the 2nd Futagoyama fortress.
After that, they will await further orders.
When the clock strikes midnight, the operation will begin.
Your food.
I don't feel like eating anything.
We leave in 90 minutes.
You're saying I'll be piloting that thing again?
Yes.
I don't want to. I don't want to feel that scared anymore.
It's terrifying...! But l can't even run away...
You're afraid of Eva?
Then stay and rest.
Rest?
I will pilot Unit 01.
Ayanami!
Farewell.
The Angel is penetrating through the 17th armored plate!
Target will reach NERV Headquarters in 4 minutes 55 seconds.
The new western Hakone line and the southern Tounosawa overhead line have been electrified.
Currently, the number 16 substation is continuing to establish its transformer equipment.
500,000 volts are flowing through the transformers as planned. No changes to the time sheet.
The 28th transformer group will arrive after a five minute delay.
All related persons, please hurry to your respective lines.
Begin proceeding to Stage Four of the simulation. Now re-checking recovery and support systems.
All SMES have been set up. Sequential startup from the first bundle confirmed.
All mega-high voltage superconductor transformers' opening and closing checks complete. No problems.
So this is the giant positron cannon?
The assembly was rushed, but theoretically it should work.
We're zeroing the alignment on our end and getting it ready to link with the G-type equipment.
And, well, the rest is up to you.
You mean up to the pilot.
Misato, I sure hope this works.
Shinji-kun, you were supposed to report long ago.
You chose to stay here, didn't you?
Then do your job properly.
I'm afraid of piloting the Eva...
You and the others have nothing to be afraid of.
You're always just giving orders from your base underground.
I'm the only one experiencing these terrifying things.
You all are hypocrites.
Come with me for a sec.
Fifteen years ago,
half of humanity died in the Second Impact.
If the Angels cause a Third Impact now,
humanity will die out. No one will survive.
I've heard this story countless times already.
If an Angel ever reaches Level EEE of NERV Headquarters...
an automatic self-destruct would commence.
We will sacrifice ourselves to prevent the Third Impact from happening.
Everyone who works here understands and accepts that risk.
This is...
It can't be... An Eva...!?
Not quite. The bringer of life to this planet, and the agent of its extinction...
The Second Angel, Lilith.
Lilith...?
Yes. Some believe it will act as the trigger for the Third Impact.
We fight with the Evas to protect Lilith.
That is something that only you can do.
We're entrusting the future of humanity to you and the Eva.
And why give me that painful responsibility?
No reason. Fate chose you, that's all.
But you're not the only one putting your life on the line here, Shinji-kun.
We all are.
I'll pilot it... one more time...
I will now inform you of your roles in this operation.
Shinji-kun.
Yes?
You will act as gunner in Unit 01.
Yes.
Rei, you and Unit 00 will be on defense.
The operation this time calls for utmost precision.
That's why, instead of the uncalibrated Unit 00, we chose to use Unit 01, even though it's still undergoing repairs.
Listen, Shinji-kun.
Because of the Earth's rotation, magnetic field, and gravity, the positron cannon won't fire straight.
Don't forget to take those factors into account.
You must strike the core in a single shot.
But I don't know where this one's core is.
Don't worry. There's a portion that materializes during its attack phase.
We believe that's where its core is located.
Your sniping position, as well as various factors that affect your trajectory, will all be inputted by us.
Thus, all you have to do is to follow the on-screen prompts, and fire when the center indicators meet.
The machine will handle the rest.
However only one spot has been set up to supply all of this power.
For that reason, Unit 01 cannot change its firing position.
Retreating isn't an option, then?
Correct.
So what if I miss, and the Angel shoots back?
Don't concern yourself with unnecessary thoughts now. Focus on destroying the target in one shot.
If I don't, we'll be in a big pinch, huh?
I... I am supposed to protect Unit 01?
Yes.
Understood.
It's time. Both of you, get dressed.
Yes.
You know...
we might die this time.
No.
You won't die.
I will protect you.
I'm not worth protecting...
This message was left at NERV Public Affairs Dept.
Um... This is Suzuhara.
Ikari... No, let me call you Shinji.
Shinji, we're counting on you!
Hey, this is Aida.
Ikari, do your best!
Ayanami, why do you pilot your Eva?
Because of my bond.
Your bond?
Yes. My bond.
With my father?
With everyone.
You're strong, Ayanami.
I don't have anything else.
It's time. Let's go.
Farewell.
Be aware that, as of now, it has just passed midnight.
It's time.
Shinji-kun, you chose to pilot your Eva.
If only for that, I am grateful.
Thank you.
Begin Operation Yashima!
Begin cannon pre-fire sequence.
Initiate Stage One power connect.
Roger. Switching circuits in primary and secondary substations.
Deploy all switchers. Begin power connect.
All power stations holding at maximum. 0.7 to maximum power threshold.
No problems in the power supply system.
Increasing frequency modulation capacity to 6.5 million watts.
No irregularities in any of the inverters.
Stage One circuit breaker system is operating optimally.
All districts from 1 through 803's power supply circuits are open!
Voltage stable. System frequency maintaining at 50hz.
Initiate Stage Two power connect.
Shingotenba transformer, valve open!
Shinsusouno transformer, valve open!
Following that, the Shinyugawara extra transformer will open its valve.
Voltage modulation within safety range.
Initiate Stage Three power connect.
Roger. Routing all power to Futagoyama transformer.
Maintain maximum allowable power transmission strength.
All cooling systems running at full capacity.
The superconductor energy storage groups are 78.6 percent charged.
Indicator confirms no irregularities.
Flywheel, beginning rotation.
Keeping the largest possible amount of energy converted from western Japan.
No problems detected with third connection.
Understood. Inform barricades 4 and 5
to proceed according to plan.
Pull back observation aircraft.
No. 3 ground-to-ground system, vaporized!
All according to plan. Don't pause for even a second! Next!!
No. 2 Turret Battery has been hit.
The eighth VLS group has been vaporized!
No. 4 ground-to-ground defense system, initiating attack.
No. 6 Missile Battery, obliterated.
Commencing third wave of laser attack.
Next, No. 7 Turret Battery will open fire.
Positron cannon charging. Currently at one terawatt.
Maintain condenser fans at 38000 RPM.
Compression density approaching firing threshold.
Increasing power feed.
Voltage conversion rate is at 0.019 percent.
Shut down overloaded circuit! Expedite reroute!
Power dropoff is within acceptable range.
Circuit breakers are operational. Recovery in progress.
No problems with the fourth connection.
Disable final safety device.
Raise firing hammer!
Initiating final input of sniping parameters.
Adjusting for Earth's rotation and gravity. Plus 0.0009.
Firing mechanism is automatically locking on.
Scope adjustment complete.
The photons are accelerating. 0.2 to discharge... 0.1...
Open the fifth and final connection!
Route all energy to power discharge subsystem.
Plugs 1 through 9, ready for power influx.
Proceeding with final calibration of positron acceleration chamber. No problems.
I'm not prepared for this like Ayanami is.
And I don't have the confidence to handle my Eva.
I just do what I'm told, without any reason.
Protect humanity...?
I didn't even realize I was doing such a vital thing...
So why does it have to be me?
13, 12, 11...
10, 9, 8, 7...
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Fire!
Did we get it?!
It missed?!
Impossible! Was it the timing?!
High-order energy reading detected from target!
All hands, brace for impact!
What's the status of the energy system?
It's still usable. We're already recharging!
And the positron cannon?
Still operational. Barrel cooling now in progress.
But unable to verify if another shot is possible.
No need to verify. Just do it.
Shinji-kun, are you alright?!
Hurry and get Unit 01 back into firing position!
Shinji-kun?!
Unit 01's pilot is hereby relieved of duty.
We'll entrust the task of sniping to Unit 00's pilot.
Ikari!
If he is of no use, we have no choice but to cut him off.
Please hold on!
He didn't run from piloting the Eva.
He chose not to step down of his own volition. We should entrust this to him!
Shinji, we're counting on you!
Ikari, do your best!
Please have some faith in your own son.
I will place my faith in him as well.
I'll leave it to you. Do as you please.
Thank you, sir!
Shinji-kun.
Yes...?
We're going to entrust you with all of Japan's energy...
With our future... All humanity's future...
The future of all living things that have survived...
They're all in your hands.
Try your hardest!
Yes!
Cannon locked into position.
Readjusting power discharge system.
Unit 01's G-type equipment has been purged.
Switching final firing system to manual mode.
Enemy drill tip has breached the ceiling directly above HQ!
Ready second shot!
Replacing fuse! Barrel cooling complete!
Power supply system is operating at full capacity.
Ground crew evacuation complete.
No problems with any of the discharge plugs.
Final sniping specifications data entry complete.
Any further adjustments will have to be done manually, by the pilot!
We'll reach discharge pressure in 0.2!
High-order energy readings from target again!
Crap!
Shinji-kun!
Ayanami!
The shield won't hold!
How much longer?!
Only 20 seconds!
Hurry...
Come on... Come on!
Come on!
We did it!
Ayanami!
Are you okay?!
Ayanami?! Ayanami!
Don't say things like, "I have nothing else".
Don't say sad things like "farewell," as if we'll never meet again...
Why are you crying?
I'm sorry.
I don't know what kind of expression I should have at a time like this...
It'd be best if you smiled, I think.
Let me guess-- The boy has awakened. Now we enter the general phase of the plan, yes?
That's correct. The Dead Sea Scroll Apocrypha have been fulfilled up to the Books of law.
The promised time draws near.
Not the Third again...
You never change, do you?
I look foward to meeting you, Ikari Shinji-kun.
TO BE CONTINUED
A
「It's only love」
It's only love
If I can be granted just one wish,
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo ii yo
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でもいいよ
then let me sleep by your side, wherever that may be.
「Beautiful world」
Beautiful world
mayowazu kimi dake wo mitsumeteiru
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Without regrets, my eyes are only on you.
「Beautiful boy」
Beautiful boy
jibun no utsukushisa mada shiranai no
自分の美しさ　まだ知らないの
You don't know yet, just how beautiful you are.
「It's only love」
It's only love
netemo sametemo shounen manga
寝ても覚めても少年マンガ
Whether you're sleeping or awake,
yume mite bakka jibun ga suki jyanai no
夢見てばっか　自分が好きじゃないの
You just dream of shounen manga, silly. Don't you like yourself?
nani ga hoshii ka wakaranakute
何が欲しいか分からなくて
You don't know what you want, but you can't stop wanting.
tada hoshigatte nurui namida ga hoo wo tsutau
ただ欲しがって　ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
Lukewarm tears roll down your cheeks.
iitai koto nanka nai
言いたいことなんか無い
I have nothing I want to tell you,
tada mouichido aitai
ただもう一度会いたい
I just want to meet you again.
iitai koto ienai
言いたいこと言えない
I can't say what I want to tell you,
konjou nashi kamoshirenai
根性無しかもしれない
Maybe I'm just a coward.
sorede ii kedo
それでいいけど
But that's all right too.
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If I can be granted just one wish,
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo ii yo
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でもいいよ
Please let me sleep next to you. Wherever that may be.
「Beautiful world」
Beautiful world
mayowazu kimi dake wo mitsumeteiru
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Without regrets, my eyes are only on you.
「Beautiful boy」
Beautiful boy
jibun no utsukushisa mada shiranai no
自分の美しさ　まだ知らないの
You don't know yet, just how beautiful you are.
「It's only love」
It's only love
donna koto demo yatte mite
どんなことでもやってみて
No matter what it is, give everything a try.
son wo shitatte sukoshi keikenchi agaru
損をしたって　少し経験値上がる
Even if you get hurt, it's a valuable experience.
shinbun nanka iranai
新聞なんかいらない
I don’t see the need for newspapers,
kanjin na koto ga nottenai
肝心なことが載ってない
The important things are not printed there.
saikin choushi doudai?
最近調子どうだい?
How are you doing recently?
genki ni shiteru nara
元気にしてるなら
So long as you are well,
betsu ni ii kedo
別にいいけど
I'll be fine.
boku no sekai kieru made aenu nara
僕の世界消えるまで会えぬなら
If I can't meet you before my world ends,
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo kekkou
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でも結構
Please let me sleep next to you. Wherever that may be.
「Beautiful world」
Beautiful world
hakanaku sugiteyuku hibi no naka de
儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
As these fleeting days pass by,
「Beautiful boy」
Beautiful boy
kibun no mura wa shikatanai ne
気分のムラは仕方ないね
It's natural to feel whimsical.
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If I can be granted just one wish,
kimi no soba de nemurasete
君の側で眠らせて
Please let me sleep next to you.
「Beautiful world」
Beautiful world
「Beautiful boy」
Beautiful boy
「Beautiful world」
Beautiful world
「Beautiful boy」
Beautiful boy
「Beautiful world」
Beautiful world
PREVIEW
Backup Eva 05 is sortied into action.
Unit 02 and its pilot are moved to the front lines.
Unit 04 mysteriously goes missing.
The disaster that took place when Unit 03 was forcefully activated.
And finally, Unit 06 and its pilot descend from the moon!
As Ikari Shinji continues to mentally deteriorate, where will our story lead?
Next time in Rebuild of Evangelion 2.0: Division
Next Time
Rebuild of Evangelion:
Division
--And we'll have lots of fanservice for you next time, too!